Spencer Duncan

Sr. Ruby on Rails Developer

spencerduncanpower@gmail.com

Churchville, New York, US

Sr. Ruby On Rails Developer with over 8 years of experience in software design, analysis, development, testing and implementation of web and client-server applications with 6+ years of experience in working with Ruby on Rails. Experience working in Ruby on Rails (ROR) based web applications. Expertise in developing, maintaining and debugging Rails framework. Experienced in UI development using HTML5, CSS3, AJAX, JavaScript and iQuery, React.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Railwaymen - Sr. Ruby on Rails Developer

03/2019 - 09/2022

Sansome Street San Francisco, US

- Increased daily traffic from 35% to 80% by redesigning existing websites to improve user experience and incorporated SEO technique.
- Added an additional average of 25% increase in annual company revenue with an average of 15 clients per month.
- Analyzed and improved application efficiency to 95% by optimizing queries, and code refactoring in existing applications.
- Worked alongside product managers to re-architect a multi-page web app into a single page web-app built in React resulting in a yearly revenue lift of \$1.1M
- Built the logic for a streamlined ad-serving platform that scaled to our 100M users which accelerated the page speed by 14% after implementation
- Achieved an annual savings of \$50000 by performing front and backend development; worked with clients and functional team members to understand businesses' needs designing new features.

WhiteChalkRoad - Ruby on Rails Developer

07/2017 - 02/2019

190 Bennett Street, East Perth WA 6004, Australia

- Assisted in defining procedures and methodologies for the life cycle development of a \$10 million project with Project Managers and Systems Engineers.
- Designed and completed 6 frontend applications using Rails 4, CSS3, ember.js, AJAX and jQuery.
- Led transition from firebase to AWS, saving company \$3,700+ monthly and increasing load speeds by an average of 38%.
- Gained sales growth of 25% yearly by introducing Docker to facilitate the development and deployment of microservices for the company's online database.
- Designed, developed and implemented company intranet for the use of over 1500 employees.
- Worked with a team of 5 developers to create an e-commerce platform that could scale up to 100K daily visitors.

SkySprint - Junior Ruby on Rails Developer

- Created more than 300 web pages for 35 departments and their branches, utilizing various systems, markup languages, and programming languages including HTML5, JavaScript, jQuery and React.
- Created accessible, responsive, and functional user interfaces to allow visitors on any device to have the same perfect user experience increasing number of 5 star UX/UI reviews by 135%.
- Developed user interfaces with modern JavaScript frameworks, HTML5, and CSS3, which upgraded user satisfaction by 31%.
- Invented a new system to track customer data that improved the sales process by 25%.

EDUCATION

University of Technology Sydney - Bachelor of Engineering, Engineering

04/2011 - 04/2014

15 Broadway Ultimo, NSW 2007, Australia

SKILLS

- Ruby on Rails
- Ruby
- Python
- Django
- Go
- Heroku
- Docker
- GIT
- SQL
- PostgreSQL/MySQL
- GraphQL
- RESTful API
- React
- Next.js
- AngularJS
- HTML
- CSS
- JavaScript